Contact Information

Email

fede.lopez89@gmail.com

Address

Lomas de Zamora, Buenos Aires, Argentine.

Phone

(+54911) 5501-9617

Date of birth

Mar 11, 1989

Nationality

Argentinian

Link

www.linkedin.com/in/fede ricoglopez

Skills

JAVASCRIPT
REACT
TYPESCRIPT
REDUX
NEXTJS
JEST
NODEJS
MATERIAL UI
SASS
LESS
GIT

Languages

JIRA

Spanish

Native

English

Advanced

Federico Gabriel López

FrontEnd Web Developer

I'm a Software Engineer with more than ten years of work in technology. Currently working as a Front $\!\!$ End Web Developer.

I'm a passionate individual who always wants to learn more about software engineering and computer science. I consider myself a quick learner always setting out challenges to learn different programming concepts and to find a more efficient way of solving problems.

Experience

Remote

Feb 2022 - Present

Front-End Web Developer

Bonzzu

Working for Delos Company, an American global wellness leader company, within the UI Team. Use of React as the main library for developing the components.

Remote

Aug 2021 - Apr 2022

Javascript Fullstack Web Developer

Nisum

Worked as a Fullstack Frontend Engineer for Science37, an American clinical research company. Use of Javascript, ReactJs/Redux and Sass/Styled Components for styling.

Remote

Aug 2020 - Aug 2021

Front-End Web Developer

ICBC

Development of a new internal application within the bank for the user of the Compliance area (Anti-money laundering). Use of ReactJs, NodeJs (REST APIs) with Express library and Bootstrap/Sass for the styles.

Remote

2018 - Aug 2020

Fullstack Web Developer

Freelance

Development of web applications applying the latest technologies on the market. Both frontend and backend solutions using: HTML, CSS, Javascript, ReactJs, NodeJs, MongoDB, among others.

Buenos Aires, Argentina Feb 2015 - Jul 2020

Sr Mainframe COBOL Developer

ICBC

Area: Anti-Money Laundering.

Impact analysis. Effort estimation and budget developments. COBOL programming. BATCH & Online (CICS/ALTAMIRA). Use of VSAM files, MQ and DB2. Unit, integral, and user tests.

Buenos Aires, Argentina Feb 2014 - Jan 2015

Functional Analyst Cobol

ISBAN

Area: Risk management. Review and acceptance of requirements. Preparation of technical designs for delivery to an SF. Attention to productive incidents.

Buenos Aires, Argentina Oct 2012 - Feb 2014

Sr Mainframe COBOL Developer

BBVA

Area: Market and Liabilities. Functional analysis. Impact analysis. Development of COBOL components in TSO/HOST.

Buenos Aires, Argentina Mar 2010 - Sep 2012

Cobol Developer

Accenture

Project: IBERDROLA from Spain. Development of COBOL components Batch and Cics. DB2, MQ, JCLs.

Education

BA, Argentina 2020 - 2021

FullStack NodeJs

Education IT

BA, Argentina 2008 - 2015

Computer systems Engineering National University of Technology

Incompleted. Third year reached.

BA, Argentina 2004 - 2006

Bachelor s degree in Business Administration Institute Euskal - Echea

Projects

Virtual resume: https://fedelopez89.github.io/resume/